RUPEE:
The movie is starting!
Everybody, shush, shush, shush!
You, in the back,
with the funny face
and the weird t-shirt.
You shush, too.
So, you want to hear
a fairy tale, eh?
Okay! Once upon a time...
Wait, no!
We heard that one before.
In a world...
Yes, this is good.
With millions and billions
of kids!
When they reach a certain age,
they all share
the same experience.
They lose their teeth!
Ha-ha!
But what do they do
with the tooth?
They put it
under their pillow at night.
Then, something magical
happens.
A tiny fairy comes down
to the house,
finds the sleeping child,
lifts the pillow,
and exchanges
the tooth for gold.
But why?
Why do they do this?
I think...
KINGSTON: Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
Where's Van?
Has anyone seen my son?
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
Whoa!
[YELLS]
Hey, Dad.
Feldspar, and...
[SIGHS]
You're using my birch, again.
Sorry I'm late.
Do you know how
this makes me look?
The headmaster
of tooth fairy instruction,
yet my own son skips out to ride
his preposterous
wheeled contraption!
Oh, no, my shredder!
Anyway, you have wings.
In case you haven't noticed,
fairies fly, not roll.
And in case you haven't noticed,
I have a hole in my wing.
[SCOFFS]
So I'm not very aerodynamic.
[SIGHS]
Always an excuse with you.
You're skipping class.
So I missed my final day
of tooth fairy training.
But it was the same old stuff
like you've told me
a million times before, right?
That old stuff is
the most important part.
Understanding our past is what
will make our future a success.
[♪♪♪]
Our world is based
on a codependent system.
We need the gold
from the goblins
to give to the humans.
In turn, we give fairy dust
to the goblins
to do whatever they do
to get the gold.
And, of course, the teeth
from the humans,
among the other
creatures we help,
is how we make fairy dust,
which expresses our magic.
I wanna see the goblin mines.
When it's your turn to transport
the gold carts, you will.
There's nothing to see.
Have you ever been inside?
Fairies do not enter
the mines, ever.
They are plagued with terror,
and we do not want to upset
the codependent balance we have
with those horrid creatures.
Besides, we're surface dwellers.
That's where
our magic flourishes.
Hooah!
KINGSTON:
Ha-ha!
Just finished carving this one.
Applewood, huh. I like it.
Have you been
practicing your magic?
To do anything serious,
I need you to make me
a wand like yours.
Common misconception.
The wand is like a pen,
the fairy dust like ink.
Together, they form a mere tool
which is used to express magic.
Whoa! Oh, oh! Whoa!
Oh! Whoa! Oh!
All a wand needs
is a strong fairy to wield it.
[LAUGHS]
I am strong.
More than you know,
and you have skills.
I just wish you'd put
them to better use.
Vanir, tonight
is an important night.
Are you sure you're ready
to carry on
the storied tradition of being
a tooth fairy?
Of course.
Sure wish magic could
fix my shredder.
Magic can fix your shredder.
You must learn to trust it.
Yeah, yeah, Dad.
[SIGHS]
Make sure you're home
for supper.
Hey, Dad, maybe you
can help me fix this tonight.
BARKLE:
Spider attack!
[YELLS]
The more you struggle,
the more the web sticks!
Pop-quiz! What do you do?
Barkle, let him go!
[SNIFFS]
You smell like susberries!
-Oh!
-[VAN GROANING]
So, aren't you excited
for tonight?
Not really. I mean, is this it?
From now on we're just
collecting baby teeth
for the rest of our lives?
None of this interests me.
I never use magic anyway.
You should. It's super helpful.
It's suspicious.
And you wanna know
something really strange?
Why don't fairies go
into the goblin mines?
Supposedly we're codependent,
but we don't even know
what they look like!
-Hideous.
-Ugly. Dirty.
Thieves.
-Obsessed with gold.
-BARKLE: Savages.
-FLORA: Hairy knuckles.
-BARKLE: Never leave their mine.
-Warts the size of walnuts.
-Smell like rotten eggs.
Have either of you
actually seen a goblin?
Ever?
My point exactly.
Poor thing was naked.
[ASHERAH HUMMING]
[♪♪♪]
Uh-oh. Rough day?
[SIGHS]
Still time for it to get worse.
Yeah, I spoke with your father.
Broken again?
It's because
I've been using birch.
I need wood with more pop.
Dad recommends I use maple.
You know, maybe it's a sign.
Time to get your feet
off the ground
and head in the clouds.
I can fly, Mom.
Oh? Heads up.
VAN:
See?
I just prefer my shredder.
Sweetie, you have
a special magical gift.
And if you take care
of your gifts,
they will take care of you.
Maybe it just needs
a little magic.
Come on out for dinner.
[♪♪♪]
Careful, Van.
You know how hard
your father worked on those.
They are very powerful.
Always confusing me.
It's powerful, but not magical?
That's because a fairy's magic
comes from within.
You'll find it.
Come on, magic.
Work!
[YELLS]
[SIGHS]
-ASHERAH: Van?
-[GASPS]
ASHERAH:
Everything okay?
Use your skills
to target the right homes.
Remember the key indicators.
Toys, bikes, trampolines,
discarded juice boxes.
These signs will more often than
not lead to the right children.
And remember to always
take care of your belongings.
And most importantly?
-Beware of spiders!
Is everyone ready?
Gather your coins!
I have something for you.
My father gave me a really
cool wand on my first night out.
Now, I'm giving you one.
Make me proud, son.
I will.
Here we go! Wings ready!
You can do it.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTING]
[CONTINUES GRUNTING]
[♪♪♪]
[SNORING]
[SNEEZES]
[SCREAMS]
Ow!
[GRUNTS]
[GIGGLING]
Oh!
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS, PANTS]
[SIGHS]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
Hey!
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
No, no!
Oh, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no!
[GRUNTING]
Stop!
[GASPS]
[WHIMPERS]
Whoa! [YELLS]
Hi.
[GRUNTS]
Hey, are you okay?
[COUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Hello?
[MYSTERIOUS, CREEPY NOISES]
[YELLS, GROANS]
[♪♪♪]
[LOUD WHOOSHING]
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
KINGSTON:
Guys, what happened to you?
I was chased by a cat.
Big cat. Big, scary cat.
That's not a tooth!
It's a mint!
I was bamboozled.
[LICKS]
Ah, where's Van?
Guys, I saw--
Where's your tooth?
I didn't get one.
What happened to your coin?
I dropped it, but listen--
Where is your wand?
Must have lost it!
But wait, I have a good reason.
Don't say cat.
Don't say mint.
I met a goblin. I think.
I saw this shady character,
wearing some kind of
futuristic suit,
stealing my tooth.
So I followed.
It was a girl.
She tripped,
and then her helmet came off,
and then I saw her face,
and she was so pretty.
-Pretty?
-Not a goblin.
-Futuristic suit?
I held the helmet in my hands.
And I'm telling you, I've never
seen anything like it.
It had all these lights,
and buttons, and stuff.
Oh, and then I spoke
into the mountain--
So where is this helmet?
Oh, I, uh, I left it.
It didn't belong to me.
[SIGHS]
Your actions tonight
have been disgraceful.
Or have I been
a terrible teacher?
-No, sir.
Then I want a tooth
from each of you
in my hand tomorrow night.
Are you okay, Van?
Mom!
I heard last night
didn't go so well.
Oh, uh, no.
Actually, it was awesome.
I mean, it was
an awesome first night
and learning experience.
But I'll do better tonight.
I'm sure you will.
But next time,
come up with a better story.
Pretty goblins wearing
high-tech suits?
A bit of a stretch, huh?
FLORA:
It couldn't have been a goblin!
Did she have hairy knuckles?
No, I'm telling you!
She was nothing
like you imagine.
[GRUNTING]
Whatever. Lie all you want.
[GRUNTS]
I'm not lying!
It doesn't really
matter anyway.
You still didn't get a tooth,
lost a gold coin, and...
Oh, yeah!
I can't believe you lost your
dad's super cool magic wand.
Yeah, Van.
That was a special wand.
Wow! Thanks, Flora.
I'ma get me two teeth tonight!
No mints!
Hmm.
[HUMMING]
Van.
Yes, it's basic,
but it will do the trick.
[SNIGGERS]
Okay, guys, I want you two
to stick together tonight.
Wait, what? But I--
Don't worry, bro. We got this.
[UTTERS A MUSICAL TUNE]
Wings ready!
[♪♪♪]
You know, you were just like Van
when you were younger.
That's what I'm afraid of.
The record for the most teeth
collected in one night is seven.
I'm gonna break that and become
the greatest tooth fairy ever.
Even better than
Flosston the Furious.
What do you think?
Uh, uh, Van?
Van?
Van? Van?
Van, where'd you go?
Van!
Dude, dude, scream like me
if you can hear me!
Van!
[♪♪♪]
-[RUSTLING]
-Huh?
[GRUNTS, GROANS]
[SQUELCHING]
I don't believe this.
How am I ever gonna
live this one down?
[GROANS]
The more you struggle...
RUPEE:
...the more the web sticks.
[SCREAMING]
Who-- what are you?
Who? Rupee. What? Troll.
Troll? No way.
Trolls are supposed
to be big and fierce.
Rupee is big and fierce.
[LAUGHS]
You should see
Rupee's cousin Larry.
He's terrifying.
Rupee, huh?
[GRUNTS]
Do you always refer
to yourself in the third person?
Always.
How'd you get stuck here?
Rupee was spying on the
spiders, slipped on war mud,
fell,
and was caught by this web.
Now Rupee is stuck!
You are a, uh, fairy boy?
Yes, I am.
Use your fairy boy magic
to free Rupee!
Magic never works
when I want it to.
What?
You want to be spider food?
Use your magic now!
Free Rupee!
I can't.
You can! Focus, fairy boy!
Magic is inside you!
Use your fairy wand
and free Rupee!
All right, all right.
I'll give it a try.
[SIGHS, GRUNTS]
See?
Rupee always heard
fairies were lazy.
Now Rupee understands why.
Hey, we aren't lazy!
Then concentrate harder!
[GRUNTS]
Spiders are coming! Hurry!
Focus, fairy boy! Believe!
Okay, I got this.
[RUPEE LAUGHS]
Your fairy magic is working!
Keep going!
[GRUNTS]
No! Why do you stop?
I got a better idea.
I can reach your knife.
RUPEE:
Ah, good idea. Hurry.
Ho-ho!
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTING]
You have Rupee's thanks,
but we need to--
Salutations!
Run!
Ooh, fast food! Fantastic!
[PANTING, GRUNTING]
[GROANS, GASPS, PANTS]
Where are you, my fairy friend?
Seems like you're having
trouble with your wings.
You can't hide forever.
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS, GASPS]
You again?
You saved Rupee.
Now Rupee owes you a life debt.
Oh, no need!
-[CHUCKLES]
-Hmm.
VAN: I'm sure you would
have done the same.
If you could just
give me directions
to the goblin mountain entrance,
we'll call it...
even.
Not enough!
Rupee will return the favor
and save you, fairy boy!
My name is Van.
Okay, Van.
Trolls always pay their debts.
You want to go to the mountain?
Follow Rupee.
[HUMMING]
Mm-hmm. Hmm. Mm-hmm.
So, what are you planning
to do with all that?
Rupee is making weapons.
Trolls are mighty warriors.
Right.
Trolls are the most dangerous
of all creatures.
Magical or not.
The Goblin Cave is just ahead.
Quiet. Watch.
Trolls have perfect timing.
[♪♪♪]
But how?
Shh. Rupee said quiet.
Watch. Perfect timing.
[♪♪♪]
Whoa!
Okay, show's over. Now we go.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Not yet. Where are the goblins?
No one sees the goblins.
They never come out!
That's a good thing.
Rupee heard they
were disgusting.
Oh, really?
And dangerous,
much like spiders,
but especially like trolls.
Dangerous?
[LAUGHS]
VAN:
Really? Trolls?
You're like so cute and tiny.
And you were easily
captured by that spider.
Never touch a troll's hair!
Sheesh!
Very dangerous.
Okay. Got it.
Is there another entrance?
Wait! Someone is coming.
[GASPS]
She's got my--
[♪♪♪]
I'm going.
No! Stay if you value your life.
What do you mean?
Legends say Gold Mountain
is not made by Mother Nature,
but by an ancient witch
who placed a curse
on bad fairies, thieves.
She took away their wings
and magic, made them ugly,
changed them
into terrible goblins,
and forced them to mine gold
all day and night
so that they are haunted
by the constant reflection
of their hideous and vile faces!
This is good mud.
Rupee likes mud.
Rupee does not
like tooth fairies.
Come on.
It's gotta be here somewhere.
[GRUNTS]
[MYSTERIOUS, CREEPY NOISES]
Smart fairy.
Hmm.
Not so smart fairy.
[♪♪♪]
[GRUNTS]
Oh!
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
[GROANS]
What are you doing here?
Fairies are forbidden!
Um, yeah.
I know, but I came
to get my stuff back.
[GASPS]
[LAUGHING]
You better hide!
[GOBLIN BULLY LAUGHS]
Hey, what do you
got there, Gemma?
Another one of your
nerdy science experiments?
If I told you, Rocky,
you wouldn't understand anyway.
Yeah, I'll be the judge of that.
This is mine.
Whoa!
Never seen
a real-life fairy before.
Whoa!
I thought you'd be glowing,
makin' us sneeze
from your fairy dust.
[CHUCKLING]
Whoa, what about your
silly magic, fairy?
If you don't leave,
I'll show you some magic.
Oh, yeah? Let's see it.
I wanna see it.
GOBLIN BULLY 1:
Now, where's his wand?
ROCKY:
Show us your magic!
ASHERAH:
A fairy's magic
comes from within.
-GOBLIN BULLY 2: Nice.
-GOBLIN BULLY 1: Don't worry.
Uh, what is he doin'?
Ooh!
Come on. Come on, work.
[GRUNTING]
ROCKY:
He can't do it.
You're lucky
I don't have my wand!
So lucky!
[LAUGHING]
Huh, bad enough you're a fairy.
Now you're a fairy
with no magic.
And is that
a hole in your wing?
GOBLIN BULLY 2:
It's huge.
[ROCKY LAUGHS]
Dude, can you even fly?
He's like a donut.
[GIGGLES]
Oh, I don't get it.
Holey.
[BOTH LAUGH]
GOBLIN BULLY 1:
Over here! Over here! Got-- oh!
-Safe.
-[CHUCKLING]
Boys, boys, boys.
[COUGHING]
Don't worry. I got ya.
Hey.
Have you always
had this irregularity
in your aerial appendage?
What are you doing? What?
[GRUNTS, PANTS]
The hole in your wing.
Ah, yes. It's a birthmark.
Therefore, I was born with it.
What'd you do?
I applied an adhesive patch made
of slug slime and spider's web.
Try to fly!
[INHALES, EXHALES]
Um...
Something's wrong?
Well, that didn't work
when I got here, either.
A fairy who can't fly.
I can fly.
Fairy aerial appendages
could be sensitive
to the absence of natural light.
Ah! Interesting.
Can you just call them wings?
You like my shredder?
Shredder?
Did you construct it yourself?
Sure did.
I used birch wood
for the board,
vine from Algerian ivy
as binding,
shaped feldspar sand
for the trucks,
and acorns for the wheels.
Oh! I can't believe this!
I mean, I didn't know
goblins were this...
Intelligent?
Well, yeah.
I'd always heard that they were
uneducated, grumpy, hideous,
and smelly, too.
I'm not hideous and smelly.
No, you're the exact opposite.
But I did hear that goblins
were also thieves.
We are not thieves!
You stole my tooth!
It wasn't yours.
Besides, I fairly exchanged
it for gold currency,
as is customary.
You stole my skateboard
and wand.
I found them, discarded.
What about the spider webs
you fixed my wings with?
I can take that off if you want.
No, no, it's fine. I like it.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
You're quite polite for a fairy.
Your name's Gemma?
Yes.
Van. My name is Van.
Van. Welcome to Goblin City.
So, what is all this?
I'm using the teeth
to create a drinkable cure
for our sensitivity
to natural light.
Goblins cannot survive in it.
So, you think it's the opposite
for a fairy?
We need the light to fly?
Seems plausible.
Why else are your
wings not working?
Hey, can you read?
Of course. Don't touch.
I was just, you know, testing.
What's in here?
Ooh, you'll like this.
[GASPS]
GEMMA:
It's an expulsion transport.
It's almost completed.
I just gotta figure out some
combustion propellant ratios
and...
...one day, I'll be able to fly.
Take it from a fairy,
flying is overrated.
Where would you wanna fly to?
I just want to explore.
The land, the sea, the sky.
Maybe even the cosmos one day.
That would be truly magical.
Do you use sorcery often?
You mean magic? Not really.
I mean, I've tried.
But honestly,
I'm not very good at it.
What kinds of things
can you do with magic?
Move small objects.
Shoot electrical charges.
Help plants and bugs.
Supposedly, it's useful.
If you're not very proficient
at magic,
why did you threaten
to employ it
on Rocky and his friends?
That's a weird way
of thanking me
for saving your life.
[LAUGHS]
What do you mean? I saved you!
OPAL:
Gemma?
Oh, no! My parents!
You have to hide!
[GRUNTS]
GEMMA: Stay right there,
Shroo. Don't let him out!
Gemma, what happened?
Just got a little overheated.
What are these
aerodynamic appendages?
[SIGHS]
I'm sorry.
I know I shouldn't have let
a fairy into--
Ah, fairy wings! Now I see it.
Oh, I mean, yes,
those are fairy wings.
VAN:
Ow!
And why are you
diagramming fairies?
You know those surface dwellers
are lazy and carry a sense
of entitlement.
VAN:
What?
And may carry rabies, too.
Oh, honey, those
are just rumors.
I don't know.
I think fairies are kinda cute.
Ugh, this place is a mess.
We really wish you'd channel
your energies
into something productive.
Like more efficient
mining equipment?
Yes, exactly.
Magical cures
for weathering daylight
and the possibility
of goblin flight
are impractical.
Well, maybe there are things
we can learn from fairies.
Remember what happened
to your grandmother?
She too had a tooth fascination
that led to--
Led to her disappearance.
Yes, I know.
But I'm sure the fairies didn't
have anything to do with it.
There's a balance
that we must not upset.
Okay, okay,
she's a teenager, Orum.
Save the lecture.
Let's give her some space.
Please get this
cleaned up, okay?
[SIGHS]
[♪♪♪]
Maybe they're right.
Are you kidding?
If you wanna be
the first space goblin,
you gotta keep trying.
We better vacate
before anyone else finds you.
You'll need a disguise.
[♪♪♪]
Wow!
I've never seen so much gold.
Your fairy dust is
very important to us goblins.
It powers our entire city,
allowing us to continue
our mining operations.
It's...
VAN:
A codependent system.
Right.
[LAUGHING]
Now we're gonna go to the gym.
It's leg day.
[GRUNTS]
[GIGGLES]
I can always make another one.
Everyone is so wrong
about goblins.
We're mostly good-natured.
Mostly.
Gold digger.
[LAUGHS]
Back in your lab, is it true
what you said to your parents?
That-- that you thought some
fairies might be cute?
Goblins have been known
to obscure the truth
from time to time.
But I have to admit, we seem
to have a lot of misconceptions
about tooth fairies as well.
Tell me about it.
Well, you do assume that every
kid's tooth belongs to you.
Good point, but we're not lazy!
Hmm.
You did display courage
and determination
when attempting
to reclaim my tooth.
And we don't have rabies!
That's to be determined.
[GASPS]
What a wondrous feeling
it must be
to find your soul mate.
I'm sure yours is in
this mountain somewhere.
Thanks.
I think we took a wrong turn.
[LAUGHS]
[♪♪♪]
What your dad said
about your grandma--
We called her Gigi.
Is it true?
I wanna show you
one last place.
[♪♪♪]
Come on.
This was Gigi's
favorite destination.
This place is amazing!
GEMMA:
Indeed.
Goblins don't patronize this
planetarium anymore
since the technology
is archaic.
Additionally, it seems they're
satisfied with just staying
in the ground.
GIGI:
The beginning of time
and the universe...
GEMMA:
That's Gigi.
She was the last director
of this place.
...also marks the beginning
of goblin history.
That is represented among
the stars in the constellation
of Graygor's Gold,
which is predominantly seen
in the Northern Hemisphere
since it is
a circumpolar constellation,
along with a recently
discovered star pattern
called
Flight of the Tooth Fairy.
[CHUCKLES]
GEMMA:
She loved to explore.
Definitely inherited
her passion.
I can see why.
One day,
I'm going to see it all.
Whoa! Is this real?
I believe it's factual.
Where was this photo taken?
That's the enigma. No one knows.
She supposedly discovered
a special place
that contained secrets
to the past.
But she disappeared
before she could reveal
its precise location to anyone.
The harsh winter
displaced many creatures
to Molar Mountain,
including a village of trolls
and a legion of vicious spiders.
This was the last gift
she gave to me.
Looks like the top of a heart.
Maybe she had the other half?
As director of the planetarium,
I'd like to thank you
for visiting and encourage you
to explore.
Meanwhile,
don't stop believing!
Show's over. Time to go.
Will your dad be angry
if you return without a tooth?
Maybe.
But I'm bettin' that givin' his
wand back will soften him up.
So who's the thief now?
[BOTH LAUGH]
[GASPS]
Maybe your experiments
just need a little fairy dust.
Seriously? All this for me?
If it powers our magic,
then it might help you.
Don't stop believin'. Right?
Can it be consumed?
Oh, yeah!
We use dust on everything.
Just know, there's, like,
bug hair and stuff in there.
Can we-- do you think--
well, maybe we can--
Oh, I--
I have a lot of work to do.
It was nice seeing you again.
Farewell, Van.
[SIGHS]
Bugs? Bug hair? Really?
Did I say something wrong?
Ugh.
Yeah, eat it,
we put it on everything.
Wow! She really fixed my wing!
Oh, yes!
Okay. Okay.
Let's see what you can do.
[♪♪♪]
[LAUGHS]
Whoa-ho!
Oh!
Bug hair and stuff.
[♪♪♪]
Hey!
I hope you have
a tooth behind your back.
A tooth?
[LAUGHS]
Let me explain.
So, I met this cute little
troll named Rupee,
who took me to Gold Mountain,
and I went through
this secret tunnel,
entered into Goblin City,
where I met Gemma,
that goblin girl I told you
about yesterday.
And you will not believe this,
but she fixed my wing.
See?
And then she showed me around
their amazingly
technologically advanced city
and this really cool
planetarium.
Enough!
Barkle spent the entire night
looking for you,
fearing you may have been
eaten by a spider!
I'm taking you off
of the missions.
You will work
in the processing plant,
and you are forbidden
from leaving Fairyland
until further notice.
You're all dismissed.
[SIGHS]
You found it.
I hope you'll now take
better care of it.
Too harsh?
We know Van is rebellious,
but he's not dishonest.
But a goblin?
TALUS:
A tooth fairy?
Hush! My parents will hear!
Why did he follow you?
Ugh! Is he a stalker?
No, well, because
I took a tooth he was after.
And his innovative
wheel board thing.
And his father's sorcery stick.
Anyway, he's really cute.
And cool.
Oozes in confidence, too.
Did I mention he was cute?
Strange for a tooth fairy.
This will never work.
He's a fairy.
SHEENA:
And no way he was cute.
Probably put some kind
of magical spell on you
to make you think he was--
Oh, wow, so lit!
You mean sparkly.
Yeah, that's what I said.
The natural ingredients
in fairy dust must be causing
a pH reaction with
the hydroxyapatite crystals
from the tooth enamel.
[SIGHS]
I'm gonna go watch Rocky
work out at Goldie's gym.
It's leg day. Wanna join?
Ew, but yes.
Anything more exciting
than magnesium fusion.
-No offense, Gem.
-None taken.
[♪♪♪]
It worked!
I need to procure more dust.
[♪♪♪]
All right, here goes nothin'.
[SLURPS]
Hmm, minty.
Whoa.
[♪♪♪]
Goblins above ground?
Oh, this is some juicy news!
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
Stealing again?
If the pursuit
of scientific advancement
is a crime,
I'm guilty as charged.
You got it working!
All it needed
was a little magic.
♪ Right there is destiny ♪
♪ All the possibility ♪
Hey, you're not affected
by the sunlight!
Thanks to your fairy dust.
You really should start
believing in magic more.
♪ It's comin'
to open your eyes ♪
Wow, so you can really fly!
Thanks to your patch.
And that had nothing
to do with magic.
♪ Two worlds are joined as one ♪
♪ Brighter than the rising sun ♪
♪ Oh, make a wish
and hold your heart ♪
♪ Together we'll follow
the stars ♪
♪ Feet off the ground
and your head in the clouds ♪
♪ There's beauty below to see ♪
♪ Taking a chance like a wing
on a prayer to leave ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you, old you ♪
♪ And feel a little magic ♪
♪ Like the bold you,
the boldness in you ♪
♪ Sometimes belief
is all that we need ♪
♪ For chasin' a dream to life ♪
♪ It's time to break out
to a new way, new way ♪
♪ The air in between us ♪
♪ It's the sure way,
the surefire way ♪
♪ Nothing can stop you ♪
♪ From tryin' your best
tonight ♪
♪ So take flight ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you, old you ♪
♪ And feel a little magic ♪
♪ Like the bold you,
the boldness in you ♪
♪ Sometimes belief is... ♪
So what happened to
"Farewell Van"?
The myocardium wants
what it wants.
Your myo-what?
Heart. Myocardium means heart.
Oh, right.
[SCREAMING]
♪ Nothing can stop you ♪
♪ From tryin' your best
tonight ♪
♪ So take flight ♪
One day I'm gonna catch you!
QUEEN MORTINA:
Where's my dinner, Webster?
I'm sorry, Queen Mortina,
I came up dry today.
QUEEN MORTINA:
Then I'll just eat you.
I-- I know
I came up empty-handed,
but I bring you some juicy news!
It's about the goblins!
Goblins?
They can now walk
during the day!
Are you sure?
Yes, I witnessed it
with my own eyes!
Then bring one back to me!
It's been so long
since I've savored the flavor.
Yes, my queen.
This is your final chance,
Webster.
Disappoint me again
and you shall truly
make me a widow.
Release him.
Goblins!
Pathetic, dim, silly creatures
that have always tried to go
where they don't belong.
[LAUGHS EVILLY]
Perhaps if I can somehow
regulate the airflow
in the combustion chamber,
thereby causing a periodic
delay in the ignition,
then the reaction time
is directly isolated
to the introduction
of the fairy dust,
balancing
the energy quotient ratio.
You mean you need
to mix fuel better
so you can fly longer?
I knew you'd understand
Um, Gemma, your ears?
Ugh!
Now the potion
is wearing off, too!
Hang on! It'll have to do.
Please hurry, Van.
[CHUCKLES]
[GRUNTS]
I can't believe the potion
didn't last either.
That's why I don't trust magic.
It's all unreliable.
[♪♪♪]
Aren't those...
The same drawings
that were behind Gigi
and her history book!
She was here!
[♪♪♪]
Run away, Van!
Rupee, no!
Rupee will save you
from the goblin!
Ugh! You terrible little troll!
Rupee, no! Stop!
Oh, no, you don't!
Stop!
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
Oh, no. Rupee!
Is Rupee dead?
No, buddy.
I didn't expect that.
Neither did I.
You're friends with a troll?
Come on, it's so cute.
I guess so.
Never touch a troll's hair.
Right.
Sorry about the mud,
Rupee owes me a life debt.
You're just full
of surprises, Van.
What are you doing here, Rupee?
Rupee likes this cave
with relaxing waterfall sounds.
Rupee's been coming here
for years.
May I borrow your light?
You can trust her.
[♪♪♪]
Incredible!
Wow! What does it all mean?
Simple.
Fairies and goblins
working together.
Gigi was telling the truth!
Ah, Rupee doesn't trust
cave cartoons.
Why not?
Because they don't make sense.
Gemma. You okay?
Yes, it's a lot to consider.
RUPEE:
It's nighttime soon.
Spiders are coming.
Gemma, we should go.
Rupee will show you the way.
RUPEE: A lot of people
have questions like,
"Would a spider eat Rupee?"
Yes, but what
a spider should wonder is,
"Would Rupee eat a spider?"
The answer is also yes.
Rupee would.
What do you think
about my parents meeting yours?
My dad would freak out.
GEMMA:
Mine, too.
But we have an opportunity
to change our worlds.
Think about it.
Fairies and goblins
becoming friends.
RUPEE:
And trolls?
Can trolls be friends, too?
Sure, Rupee. That sounds nice.
Good.
Goblins and fairies
need troll protection.
Right.
Ah, the goblin cave
is just ahead.
[♪♪♪]
So, you'll speak
to your parents?
It's the only way we'll be free
to see each other.
Gemma, I just wanted to say
that I really like...
Yes?
Your, um, jet pack!
See you soon.
Come on, Van!
Jet pack? Really?
Those are the words you came up
with in that perfect moment?
[CHUCKLES]
Rupee is shocked.
Why is it everything seems
to go wrong when you're around?
[GRUNTS]
Trolls have stronger game.
This is a good stick.
Mm, a fairy, a goblin...
[SNIFFS]
...and a troll?
Oh, I don't like hairy food.
This comic isn't very funny!
[♪♪♪]
[VINES SNAPPING]
[BOULDERS RUMBLING]
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
-Wait, wait, wait!
-Let me explain.
The answer is no!
It's just a meeting.
Is this a joke?
Didn't you hear anything
I just said
about the cave drawings?
About Gigi?
It's real!
We used to work together!
And they're nice and friendly.
And we can learn
so much from their technology.
But I don't think
that's a good idea.
We have a tradition to uphold.
If you care about tradition,
then you have to see
what we discovered.
This will prove to you
that Gigi was right all along.
Fine.
We will go.
But if I get rabies...
Or they are rude...
Thank you, thank you! You won't!
They aren't, I promise!
Don't forget about us!
We also wanna see the goblins!
Uh, we are coming, too!
I heard fairy boys are fly.
You mean cute.
Yeah, that's what I said.
[♪♪♪]
It was there.
It is there. Behind all these...
Busted boulders.
You mean rubble?
Yeah, that's what I said.
Aren't goblins supposed
to be superior miners?
Perhaps you could excavate
this mess.
Of course.
Oh, wait, I left my pickax
in my other robe.
[TALUS SNIFFS]
You smell like susberries.
Thanks.
What about employing your magic?
We're not in the goblin business
of moving mountains.
Well, that's exactly where
we're going now.
Back to the mountain.
At least you know
where a goblin's place is.
Huh, entitled fairies.
Good tidings, goblins.
It was nice to meet you.
Yes, perhaps
under different circumstances.
Different timing.
Shall we--
Give them a moment.
Indeed.
I can't believe this.
No, no, no.
Don't stop believing.
Let's run away.
Where would we go?
Anywhere.
I don't wanna collect kid teeth
for the rest of my life.
Let's be free to fly!
Remember where we saw each other
for the first time?
Tomorrow night.
I'll meet you there.
[♪♪♪]
Let's go.
GEMMA:
It's an adventure!
Okay, yes, he's cute,
but, Gemma,
have you seriously
thought this through?
It's a terrible idea!
I'm sure tooth fairy traditions
will survive without me.
Do you realize
how enormous the world is?
No, we actually don't know.
You should visit
the planetarium.
[SIGHS]
And both of you would
happily carry my load of teeth.
You never carried any teeth.
My point exactly.
SHEENA: But what about
surviving in the light?
You don't have a cure!
I'm actually super close.
Shroo, no!
[GASPS]
[♪♪♪]
That's it!
What's "it"?
The cure!
I just had a breakthrough
and I need to go test it out.
I'm so confused.
Gonna miss you, Van.
I'll miss you, too, dude.
Hey, just remember,
because of me,
you're gonna collect more teeth
than any fairy ever.
Every girl likes to get
flowers.
Even a goblin girl.
I'll miss you, too,
little buddy.
I am entitled.
Headmaster
Tooth Fairy Instructor.
That's my official title.
No, entitled as in rude.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
[♪♪♪]
[SNORING]
Going somewhere, goblin girl?
[GROANS]
Gotcha!
[YELLS, GROANS]
[♪♪♪]
Run, goblin, run!
[GRUNTING]
Hello, my itsy bitsy goblin!
[SCREAMS]
[SNORES]
[♪♪♪]
Gemma, are you here?
Oh, no.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
[GROANS]
My queen is so eager
to taste goblin again.
She'll be so satisfied savoring
your skin!
[SNICKERING]
Nothing is stronger
than the spider's silk.
Struggle,
and it only strengthens.
Hello, my queen,
I have a succulent surprise
for you!
[♪♪♪]
He did it. Time for a feast!
Let's move!
[ASHERAH GASPS]
Kingston!
Oh, my fairy godmother!
Ran away?
With that fairy boy?
-Maybe?
-Probably.
It's right here in the note!
We told him it was a bad idea.
That still makes you
an accomplice.
[BOTH GASP]
They may be in danger.
We have to look for them now!
Where do we start?
Logically, they'd meet
in the middle.
The Dark Forest.
There are spiders in the forest!
Then we'll be prepared.
Just in case.
I have my pickax!
What about the moonlight?
What a sneaky--
Headstrong--
Industrious--
-Daughter we have.
How-- how did she...
It's you she takes after.
[GROANING]
Gemma!
[GRUNTS]
Behind you!
[GROANS]
Oh, no!
Surrender, fairy boy,
or I'll expose
your goblin girlfriend
to the moonlight.
[GRUNTS]
My Queen Mortina
likes her goblin meat
not too braised.
[WEBSTER SNICKERS]
[GROANS]
Van, look out!
Ha-ha!
[GASPS]
[YELLS, GROANS]
Mm-hmm,
two meals for the price of one.
[GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
Oh, magic, I love you.
Ugh. Not again.
That was amazing, Van!
[GASPS]
Foolish fairy!
I was only playing dead.
Your magic tickled.
[SNICKERS]
Don't worry!
It's all going to be over soon.
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
[SIGHS]
You again?
Oh, what rock
did you crawl out of?
Don't you have a tooth to steal?
Hi again.
Greetings.
You look magical.
Thanks! I am.
Sweet pickax.
I like your arms.
You mean my armor?
Yeah.
That's, uh, what I said.
This is all fairy fault.
Fairy fault?
If your daughter had--
Do not speak of my daughter.
I think it's time
we get involved.
Yeah, I think we better.
How dare you?
ASHERAH:
Excuse us!
Since we all care
about our children's safety...
We have decided
to work together.
You two can either join us...
Or return home.
Well?
[SIGHS]
Truce?
Truce.
If Van never went
to Goblin City...
And Gemma never made it
to Fairyland...
Where else could they be?
Gemma, the moon.
I know.
Don't be afraid. There's time.
We can get out of this.
-Together.
My queen likes to make
a dramatic entrance.
[♪♪♪]
Well done, Webster!
[GAMMA GASPS]
My grandmother's pendant.
Ah, yes. I see the resemblance!
She was the last goblin
I had the pleasure of eating.
You monster!
[LAUGHS]
I wonder,
will you taste the same?
Don't you dare touch her.
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS EVILLY]
[SCREAMS]
Gemma!
It came from over there!
[PANTS]
Wait!
[♪♪♪]
[GASPS]
What do you suggest we do?
We should split up.
This way, if one of us
gets stuck--
The other is not out
of the fight.
Fairies, follow me.
We'll surround them.
Be wary of the spider's web.
Watch your back and above you.
Good luck.
Nothing pleases me more
than a live meal that screams!
[LAUGHS]
KINGSTON:
Stop!
[GASPS]
Mmm. What is this?
A family affair?
A family meal, my Queen!
Well, Webster.
It seems you have
outdone yourself!
ORUM:
Not so fast!
[GROWLS]
My goodness.
Yes, did I forget to mention
the gaggle of goblins?
Aren't you full of surprises?
Yes, my Queen.
Perhaps you won't make
a widow out of me after all.
[GRUNTING]
Don't worry, darlin'!
Enough!
Let's not keep
our guests waiting.
[CACKLES]
Get them!
-Hi-ya!
Look out!
-Whoa!
[GRUNT TOGETHER]
Watch for the legs!
[GRUNTS, SCREAMS]
[YELLS]
[GASPS]
QUEEN MORTINA:
Watch the armor!
[GROANS]
QUEEN MORTINA:
It's strong!
[GRUNTING]
These suits are amazing.
Get up!
[YELLS]
KINGSTON:
Watch your back! That's it!
Guard your backside!
KINGSTON:
Go, fairies!
[GRUNTING]
-KINGSTON: Over here!
-FAIRY: Watch your flank!
Charge!
OPAL:
Split around the top!
They're weak at the knee!
[YELLING] Yeah! Awesome!
ORUM:
Jump on the spurs!
[♪♪♪]
[YELLING]
GOBLIN 1:
Hey, I'm shot! Hey!
-[GROANS]
-Barkle!
GOBLIN 2:
Get out of the way!
-I'm fine!
-GOBLIN 1: No!
[GRUNTING]
[INDISTINCT YELLING
IN BACKGROUND]
Oh, no, my axe!
He's too high!
You take that one!
ASHERAH:
A fairy's magic
comes from within.
KINGSTON:
You must learn to trust it.
RUPEE:
Focus, fairy boy! Believe!
[GROANS]
BARKLE: Van is free! Van's free!
Van's free!
Cover me!
[PANTS]
[SCREAMS]
Van!
Webs!
[YELLING]
GOBLIN 2:
The webs! They're shootin' webs!
Watch out!
[VAN GROANING]
Cover me.
Get some!
[PANTS]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[♪♪♪]
That's my boy!
[SCREAMS]
Get away from my son, you--
Enough games!
KINGSTON:
Watch out for webs!
[SCREAMS]
[LAUGHS]
[GROANING]
Help!
ORUM:
The webs are too tight.
[GROANING]
BARKLE:
Man, it's just too strong!
TOOTH FAIRY:
I can't get out!
[GROANING]
Now we feast.
-[FAIRY] Help!
-[MUFFLED YELLING]
Oh, what a night!
I will have the strongest
spider army in the world!
We will infiltrate
the goblin mountain
and the fairy village,
and make them ours!
[SCREAMS]
Now, little goblin.
Where were we?
I'm famished
after that bit of exercise.
[HORN SOUNDING]
Now what?
Ha!
So much noise coming from
such a horrid little creature!
[INDISCERNIBLE CHATTER]
TROLL 1:
There they are.
Where are they?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[YELLING]
QUEEN MORTINA:
What is all this?
I've never tasted troll before.
My queen, I must confess.
I did not invite
the trolls to dinner!
Nonsense,
we can make some room
for these appetizers!
[GASPS]
Rupee!
Trolls always repay debts.
Your reign of spider terror
has met it's end!
[LAUGHING]
Destroy them!
[YELLING]
[ULULATES]
[CLAMORING]
[♪♪♪]
Mud?
Is that the best
you trolls can do?
-TROLL: Watch the legs!
-[CLAMORING]
Stop!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
What are you waiting for?
Attack!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
It's a trap!
What is happening, Webster?
Hey!
Never touch troll hair.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Very dangerous.
-Shake it off.
You vile, nasty,
horrid little trolls!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER, YELLING]
[♪♪♪]
No, no, no!
My spinners, blocked!
Mine, too! Ow!
Webster, this is all your fault!
The pain!
[YELLING]
Save us, sovereign queen!
Let go of me, you fool!
This isn't over!
I'll get you, trolls!
[YAWNS]
QUEEN MORTINA:
All of you.
And the fairies, and goblins!
None of you will ever be safe
from my wra--
[SCREAMS]
TROLL 2:
We got 'em!
[TROLLS CHEERING]
Okay, free them.
Okay, you're welcome.
Larry saved you.
Oh, you did it, sir.
Rupee! Where's Gemma?
Rupee is very sorry!
Oh, no.
Gemma!
Gemma! Can you hear me?
It's faint, but her heart
still beats!
[♪♪♪]
Gemma's potion!
I know how to help her.
Let me do this.
[♪♪♪]
Holy molars!
That was some magic trick!
[LAUGHS]
[CHEERING]
[♪♪♪]
I believe your life debt
has been paid
several times over, Rupee.
Rupee told you trolls would
protect fairies and goblins!
This is Rupee's cousin Larry.
Oh, yes!
The most terrifying troll
of them all?
Yes! Larry also the mightiest!
Rupee also thinks
he's the ugliest.
Thank you!
[LAUGHING]
RUPEE:
And that's how
our new world began.
The curiosity of one girl
and one boy
who followed their hearts,
which led to the discovery
of what is now known as
Magic Golden Tooth Fairy Dust,
allowing goblins
to endure natural light,
and tooth fairies
to operate without it,.
[GROANING]
RUPEE:
So we may continue
to prosper together
as one society,
with a future
of endless possibilities.
Hey, make a wish.
It's gonna come true.
How do you know?
Magic.
[♪♪♪]
♪ Right there is destiny ♪
♪ All the possibility ♪
♪ You are strong,
you are wise ♪
♪ It's the moment
to open your eyes ♪
♪ Feet off the ground
and your head in the clouds ♪
♪ There's beauty below to see ♪
♪ Taking a chance like a wing
on a prayer to leave ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you, old you ♪
♪ And feel a little magic ♪
♪ Like the bold you,
the boldness in you ♪
♪ Sometimes belief
is all that we need ♪
♪ For chasin' a dream to life ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you ♪
♪ Two worlds are joined as one ♪
♪ Brighter than the rising sun ♪
♪ Oh, make a wish
and hold your heart ♪
♪ Together we'll follow
the stars ♪
♪ Feet off the ground
and your head in the clouds ♪
♪ There's beauty below to see ♪
♪ Taking a chance like a wing
on a prayer to leave ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you, old you ♪
♪ And feel a little magic ♪
♪ Like the bold you,
the boldness in you ♪
♪ Sometimes belief
is all that we need ♪
♪ For chasin' a dream to life ♪
♪ It's time to break out
to a new way, new way ♪
♪ The air in between us ♪
♪ It's the sure way,
the surefire way ♪
♪ Nothing can stop you ♪
♪ From tryin' your best
tonight ♪
♪ So take flight ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ It's time to break out
from the old you, old you ♪
♪ And feel a little magic ♪
♪ Like the bold you,
the boldness in you ♪
♪ Sometimes belief
is all that we need ♪
♪ For chasin' a dream to life ♪
♪ It's time to break out
to a new way, new way ♪
♪ The air in between us ♪
♪ It's the sure way,
the surefire way ♪
♪ Nothing can stop you ♪
♪ From tryin' your best
tonight ♪
♪ So take flight ♪
♪ Oh ♪